Eliza Weisman

December 29, 2016

I'M A COMPUTER SCIENTIST, engineer, and researcher. I love solving interesting and challenging problems, learning new things, and making neat stuff. My primary interests are programming languages, systems programming and operating systems, and tools for software engineering.

hi@hawkweisman.me 990 First Street, Meadville, PA 16335 (814) 853-1501

Skills

I have a lot of experience with functional programming techniques in a number of languages, and a focus on writing high-quality, idiomatic code. I'm also familiar with modern software development techniques, practices, and tools, and I've worked in a number of areas, such as web development, programming languages, and systems programming. Some of my favourite tools include:

LANGUAGES Fluent in Scala, Rust, Python, and Java; familiar with Haskell, Clojure, C, and R

LIBRARIES Frameworks: Scalatra, Bootstrap, Polymer; testing: ScalaTest, ScalaCheck, QuickCheck, JUnit, Mock-

ito: other: Akka, Slick

TOOLCHAIN Build systems: Gradle, SBT, Ant, Cargo, Make; editors and IDEs: Atom, SublimeText, IntelliJ IDEA;

collaboration: GitHub, GitLab, Jenkins, Travis

Education

I'M PURSUING A BACHELOR OF SCIENCE in Applied Computing with a focus in Software Engineering. My coursework has included:

Data Structures and Algorithms
Computer Organization

Analysis of Algorithms
Operating Systems

Principles of Software Engineering
Principles of Data Management
Programming Language Implementation

Data Communication and Networks
Introduction to Compiler Design
Robotics and Multi-Agent Systems

B.S. IN APPLIED COMPUTING Allegheny College, Meadville, PA Expected May 2016 GPA:3.67

Experience

Wrote a simple operating system kernel for x86_64, primarily in Rust, to learn more about OS design and development. Implemented a bootloader in x86 assembly, and interrupt handling, memory allocation, VGA console and PS/2 keyboard drivers, and other operating system features in Rust.

FALL 2015 — ONGOING Personal Project https://github.com/hawkw/ sos-kernel

COFOUNDED A SMALL BUSINESS to develop and publish independently developed computer games, and designed and implemented a game engine in Scala, contributing over 9,000 lines of Scala source code to the project.

Spring 2014 — Ongoing MeteorCode Laboratories https://github.com/meteorcode/ pathway

Designed and implemented Mnemosyne, a new functional language intended for systems programming, implementing a compiler in Rust using LLVM, and wrote a language specification.

Fall 2015 — Ongoing Senior Thesis Allegheny College https://github.com/hawkw/mnemosyne

Designed and implemented Seax, a virtual machine-based runtime for programs in functional languages. Wrote the VM and a compiler for Scheme programs in Rust.

SPRING 2015 Independent Study Allegheny College https://hawkweisman.me/seax